<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data science | Da Venchei Codes</title>
    <link>https://davencheicodes.com/tag/data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://davencheicodes.com/tag/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>data science</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Venchei Sanders © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://davencheicodes.com/media/share_image.jpeg</url>
      <title>data science</title>
      <link>https://davencheicodes.com/tag/data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Teaching to Tech</title>
      <link>https://davencheicodes.com/talk/2021-ds30-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davencheicodes.com/talk/2021-ds30-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-teaching-to-tech&#34;&gt;From Teaching to Tech&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I speak with Pragmatic Institute’s Michael Cullen to discuss how becoming an educator has informed my work as a practitioner and some of my thoughts for those looking to break into the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mentions-in-the-podcast&#34;&gt;Mentions in the Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davencheicodes.com/post/2021-01-25-reflection-on-transitioning&#34;&gt;Advice for Career Switchers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davencheicodes.com/post/2021-01-11-shop-time-insider-take&#34;&gt;Shop Time and the Area of a Square - Industry Insider Take&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shop Time and the Area of a Square - Industry Insider Take</title>
      <link>https://davencheicodes.com/post/2021-01-11-shop-time-insider-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davencheicodes.com/post/2021-01-11-shop-time-insider-take/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://davencheicodes.com/post/2021-01-11-shop-time-insider-take/index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shipt.tech/shop-time-and-the-area-of-a-square-dcc9cb055368&#34;&gt;Shop Time and the Area of a Square&lt;/a&gt; is an article written on July 20th, 2020 for my current employer, a grocery delivery company called Shipt, to articulate how we leveraged data analytics to understand the minimum shop time for finding one item at a retailer. Upon further review, that process has taught me a lot about developing machine learning models in industry. So I’d like to revisit the article with some additional commentary and insights on how Analytics drive ML Model Development (in industry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From time to time, I enjoy listening to the Lex Fridman Podcast and recently I heard him interviewing Charles Isbell and Michael Littman; for anyone attempting to enter the space and deploy a machine learning model, the clip below is the ML gospel; I hope you enjoy it. 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An astute modeler should know that a clever or fancy algorithm can lose or perform equally to a simpler model with superior data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8wVXyT7gKxI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you didn’t know - it’s the data, stupid! Stay close to the data because she’s your friend. The entire interview can be heard/watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/yzMVEbs8Zz0&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~pedrod/papers/cacm12.pdf&#34;&gt;A Few Useful Things to Know About Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; is another article that I found insightful about the use of data in algorithms and the desired goal of the Data Scientist or Modeler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;why-is-industry-different-part-1&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is Industry Different (Part 1)?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In industry, the data is messy. In academics, not as much. Academic programs at both the undergraduate and (some) graduate levels ignore the Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) aspect of model development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, emphasis is not on the deployment of an advance method or model. As Charles Isbell has said, “the data is almost more important than the algorithm”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’d like to go deeper. Below is the distribution of Shop Times for single-item orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/shop_times_dist0.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you go - with a few lines of code in both R and SQL - we made a graph. Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what do we know about the actual task of shopping from this distribution? Some thoughts (after reading the graph from left to right):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people are really fast shoppers with some data being negative (see the little blip on the left side of the graph)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The largest spike (aka mode) appears to occur at less than a minute of actual shopping time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At roughly three minutes we see a peak, followed by decreasing instances of longer shop times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A very long right tail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that exercise shows the limited nature of seeing data only through the lens of the numbers on a table or graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual task of shopping an order cannot be understood merely by staring at a graph and hypothesizing about shopper behavior. At Shipt, I am also a shopper. This business is about people, not machine learning models. So I physically did the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/venchei_shopper.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Venchei Shipt Shopper&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
I went into the field as an ‘undercover’ Shipt Shopper. 😉
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving students curated datasets dismisses how the game is played in reality and leaves a hole in the students’ fundamental training. Sometimes you gotta go into the field and actually do some heavy lifting (or shopping).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I open the Shipt Shopper app and see an order such as the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:offercard&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images/order_offer_og.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;OG - Order Offer Card&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: OG - Order Offer Card
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I want the experience of working as a professional Shipt Shopper, I skate to Foods Co. and shop a couple orders together. I believe (more seasoned) shoppers refer to these as ‘doubles’. This was a rookie mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see while shopping in Alabama, I had a car. I’ve since relocated to my companies’ San Francisco office and currently commute via electric skateboard and public transportation such as BART or rideshare (LYFT/UBER).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shopping a ‘double’ resulted in the following at checkout:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/cart.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Grocery Cart&#34; width=&#34;55%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
A Full Cart! 😓
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/cashier.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Checking Out&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
At Checkout
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That experience led to some internal discussions about ‘uncovering’ order metadata such as its contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the image below you see two twelve-packs of Crush orange soda and two six-packs of Sunny D. This order was very heavy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/backpack.jpg&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovations by the Shipt Product team led to the modern version of the Offer Card where shoppers can now see the underlying order contents via the List Preview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/offer_card.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Shopper Offer Card&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Shopper Order Offer Card
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/preview.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;List Preview&#34; width=&#34;35%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Order List Preview
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see the model development process (in industry) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;does not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; consist of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read about a cutting edge algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find some data at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement cutting edge algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business makes a lot of money and you get rich.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model development process (in industry) consist of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Business Problem: &lt;em&gt;What problem are you trying to solve?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Data: &lt;em&gt;Do you have the data needed to solve the problem? Do you need to create an ETL pipeline for the data?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Cleaning and Mining: &lt;em&gt;Not all data is good data. Choose wisely!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exploration with charts and graphs is always a winner but conduct some field research.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Baseline: &lt;em&gt;Set the baseline with a simple linear model, benchmark or heuristic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feature Engineering: &lt;em&gt;Feature Engineering is domain specific. So know your business and your customer. Also, checkout Max Kuhn’s book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feat.engineering/&#34;&gt;Feature Engineering and Selection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Repeat: &lt;em&gt;Iterate and repeat steps 4-6 until you find the best performing model versus your benchmark or heuristic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deployment: &lt;em&gt;Get it into production.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anomaly Detection: &lt;em&gt;Model’s decay and drift over time. Automate the detection of anomalies becuase they will happen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this business is about people and solving problems for them, not machine learning models. To actually understand the problem, I went into the Shopper App and delivered orders for members. I then leveraged that research and those experiences to help me get to know the data, its strengths and weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-about-model-performance&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What About Model Performance?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How well should a model perform? As my Econometrics Professor Matt Holt would say, “Depends on your Employer”. If we trained our model on data including possible outliers (on the left end of the distribution) then the model will perform poorly. Suppose you run a bank, under-predicting the model’s target (Shop Times for Shipt) could lead to financial ruin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you’re a head coach preparing the team for a track meet or basketball game. As the coach, do you want the athlete that has trained for the event with ten mediocre practices or an athlete with 1000 days of varying forms of practice (shooting three pointers, free throws, layups, etc); The data matters, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PERIOD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When modeling, generalization and representation matters. Stay close to the data and remember, “the data is almost more important than the algorithm.” A clever or fancy algorithm can lose or perform equally to a simpler model with superior data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, let’s get back to the article…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-long-does-it-take-to-find-one-item-in-a-grocery-store&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How long does it take to find one item in a grocery store?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and take a guess, I’ll wait… What did you guess - ten, fifteen minutes? When conducting personal shopping such a thought may come to mind while under a time crunch. What if it’s lunch time and you only have 40 minutes to run into the grocery store to grab dinner and snacks before you have to pick up the kids from day care. So how long does it take to find one item in a grocery store? Is that item in the front or rear of the store? Do you need help from a store associate while searching for that one item?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I too wrestled with this question. While working as an analyst for Shipt, I leverage common notions in both geometry and physics to determine which data are useful for a machine learning project that estimates what we call &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Shop Time”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-is-shop-time&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Shop Time?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shop Time is the duration of time from start to finish, that is needed to find an item and checkout. Shipt deeply values it’s relationship with our members and shoppers. Thus, surfacing Shop Time expectations allows a shopper to better plan, be more efficient, and provide an amazing experience for the member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When developing a model, deciding which data to value is paramount. Data selected to train a model is important as our model predictions will be consumed by our shoppers via what we call the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;offer card&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shipt Shoppers can preview an order by looking it’s offer card - a card located in-app that provides order details. The image below is an order offer card from the Shipt Shopper App. The 1 hour 15 minute estimate is not only the shop time but also the drive time; moreover, the order has 53 total items, with an estimated pay of &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(24\)&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(32\)&lt;/span&gt; tip not included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:offercard20&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images/offer_card.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Order Offer Card&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;20%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Order Offer Card
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;identifying-outliers&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Identifying Outliers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we choose data that was poorly captured then model predictions will result in a false signal and wildly varying shop time expectations for our shoppers. Therein lies the tricky part of the problem, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/understanding-the-bias-variance-tradeoff-165e6942b229&#34;&gt;Bias-Variance Trade-Off&lt;/a&gt;. Removing too much data decreases our Bias but increases our Variance (aka over-fitting to the training examples).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;why-is-industry-different-part-2&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is Industry Different (Part 2)?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, while studying economics as a graduate student, this idea was not well articulated. Outliers and bad data can destroy model performance In academics, data sets are generally cleaned such that students can quickly get up to speed on the methods and algorithms but more time should be devoted to Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) and proper Outlier identification and Removal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/predicting-vs-explaining-69b516f90796&#34;&gt;explain vs predict&lt;/a&gt; paradigm has lead to this dynamic. Economists love to explain relationships and thus seek an optimal fit that can best explain market behavior; an economist might argue, “It’s all just statistics.” In return, the ML modeler might argue that if the goal is accurate predictions then the explanation is not a relevant concern; thus, they demand generalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is true, a proper model must generalize well to new data. In this case, we started the data selection process by determining reasonable lower bounds for Shop Time. Additional resources/literature on this topic can be found by reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datascienceblog.net/post/commentary/inference-vs-prediction/&#34;&gt;Inference vs Prediction&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdsr.mitpress.mit.edu/pub/a7gxkn0a/release/6&#34;&gt;A Balanced Perspective on Prediction and Inference for Data Science in Industry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get back to the article….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In physics, there’s a well known mental model called &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/2018/04/first-principles/&#34;&gt;First Principles Reasoning&lt;/a&gt;. Thinking via First Principles allows a person to start from scratch while questioning every known assumption about a specific domain, then building a new (hopefully innovative) solution based upon new thinking about those assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong analyst should have many tools in the toolbox, reasoning by First Principles is one such tool. After thinking deeply about a reasonable floor, one should consider the most basic order type, an order (smallest possible) with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; one item. We’ll call the associated shop time for a single-item order the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimum Shop Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how long does it take to find one item in a grocery store? If you guessed 10 minutes, then I need you to explain why. As my friend Maliha would say, “In God we trust. All others must provide data.” This the art of Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to create a model that has high value impact for a business, a modeler should start by framing the problem in the most basic form, build an understanding of the limitations of the data and then find the balance between signal and noise (or Bias and Variance) for your target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, all data collected would correspond perfectly to the timestamps of the user interaction within the app. However, weather, buildings and associated natural interference leads to suspicious data captured in the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve observed outliers such as shop times that are negative, null, less than one minute, or – on the extreme right – up to 12 hours. To develop a model that reasonably represents the actual task of shopping, we had to consider the minimum time it takes and remove recorded data that may be incorrectly captured by the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the distribution of Shop Times at Shipt for single-item orders. This graph has been enhanced with a line to delinate possible outliers and colorized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:offercard10&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images/shop_times_dist1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Our database captured hundreds of zero or negative shop times.&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Our database captured hundreds of zero or negative shop times.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;grocery-shopping-axioms-and-theory&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grocery Shopping Axioms and Theory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you studied mathematics, you have probably heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euclid%27s_Elements&#34;&gt;Euclid’s Elements&lt;/a&gt;. Euclid’s Elements is a set of books attributed to Euclid of Alexandria, around 300 BC. During that time, Euclid’s Elements were considered a bible of sorts for mathematics. His theories on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Number_theory&#34;&gt;Number Theory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geometry&#34;&gt;Geometry&lt;/a&gt; are considered fundamental to a proper mathematics education. Moreover in mathematics, understood truths are called Axioms and Postulates. Here we present our Elements (Axioms and Postulates) for Grocery Shopping:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An order for delivery has a minimum of one product and one item (Shipt refers to this as an order line - similar to a line item on a receipt)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shop Times are positive, real numbers, &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\({\rm I\!R} ^ {+}\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;As number of products and total items requested increases, so does the duration of time to shop&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This article attempts to narrow the focus of number two; meaning we’re really interested in understanding which data to value for training examples. For additional reading on the Data Valuation and Quality, read some on &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1904.02868.pdf&#34;&gt;Data Shapley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have data about the area (or size) of stores that we service. Moreover, we can leverage that information along with member feedback to develop a model that reasonably estimates the time it takes to shop a single-item order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to meet or exceed delivery expectations, an experienced shopper will maximize their time by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shipt Members assume and expect the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arriving at the store early&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When appropriate, communicating order issues quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivering all requested and available products on-time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s suppose you’re a shopper who received our Minimum Shop Time order. Ok, you have an easy order. It’s only one item. What could go wrong? Well, what if the item is in the back of the store? How long might it take you to get there? How could you minimize this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;why-is-industry-different-part-3&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is Industry Different (Part 3)?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the dynamics of real world liability is something that is a miss in academic programs; meaning - what is at risk? In predicting shop times, we’d prefer to over-predict than under-predict. If you drive an autonomous vehicle, would you prefer the system over-predict, have a false positive and stop prematurely or under-predict, have a false negative and stop too late?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If designing an ABS system that uses computer vision to calculate crash probabilities mid-drive, you’d prefer the system stop early, a false positive, than late or not at all. These dynamics take the problem from ‘fun exercise’ to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/3010TVhWwXy2N9OUGQ/giphy.gif&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All funny gifs aside, let’s get back to the article…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume the store’s perimeter is that of a rectangle, particularly a square, and that information regarding the size of the grocery store is known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/square.png&#34; width=&#34;65%&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you remember from grade school, the area of a square is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
   \mbox{(Equation I.)} \substack{\text{Area} \\ \text{of a Square}} = (\mbox{Length of the Side}) ^ {2}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, via the Pythagorean Theorem, the length of the diagonal is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
   \mbox{(Equation II.)} \substack{\text{Length of the Diagonal} \\ \text{of a Square}} = \mbox{Length of Side} * \sqrt{2}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking the square root of (Equation 1), (&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\sqrt[]{(\mbox{Length of the Side}) ^ {2}}\)&lt;/span&gt;), we now have a way to determine the length of the side of the store; more importantly, the shortest possible distance through the store - a straight line!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this violates the laws of reality, a shopper likely cannot traverse the diagonal of a grocery store; but, it provides an important insight that we will leverage when we select the data for our model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if there was a way to relate this distance and time then we could evaluate the earlier guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;physics-insert-equations-of-motion&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Physics: Insert {Equations of Motion}…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In physics, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equations_of_motion&#34;&gt;equations of motion&lt;/a&gt; are equations that describe the behavior of a physical system in terms of its motion as a function of time (i.e. how fast can a Shipt Shopper cross a distance). Let’s leverage the rate, time, and distance relationship of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
   \mbox{Walking Pace} * \mbox{Shop Time} = \mbox{Distance Traveled}
\]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
  \mbox{By division, Shop Time} = \frac{\mbox{Distance Traveled}}{\mbox{Walking Pace}}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional functional forms may include the following,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
  \substack{\text{Shop} \\ \text{Time}} = \frac{\sum{\mbox{Distance Traveled}}}{\mbox{Walking Pace}} + \frac{\sum{\mbox{Items in Order}}}{\mbox{Item Identification Pace}} + ... + \epsilon 
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\epsilon = \mbox{unexplainable error}\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A human &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walking#:~:text=Although%20walking%20speeds%20can%20vary,miles%20per%20hour%20(mph)&#34;&gt;walks&lt;/a&gt; at roughly 3.1 Miles per Hour. After converting to feet per minute, we get 272.8 feet per minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;so-whats-your-point&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;…So what’s your point?…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we know the distance to the rear of the store and our walking pace, we now have a way to determine if our time to shop guess was reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now flag Shop Times in our data that are below the computed Minimum Shop Time threshold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
  \mbox{Definition,} \substack{\text{The Minimum} \\ \text{Shop Time}} \approx \frac{\sqrt{2*\mbox{Area of a Store}}}{136.4 \frac{feet}{minute}}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;why-is-industry-different-part-4&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is Industry Different (Part 4)?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple ‘model’ filled with unrealistic expectations, right? That’s not the point of this discussion. Might - It’s the data, stupid! A simple model with superior data can outperform a more clever model with noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In graduate Econometrics courses we learn about parsimony and our preference for simpler, highly performant models. However, those models are only performant if the data is properly optimized for the correct signal. Finding that optimal signal is both an art (specific to the domain) and a science (the computational and quantitative methods) used to find signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting ML training with clean data is lovely but the art of machine learning is understanding your domain and engineering solutions that a databot can not. This requires strong analytics and possibly going into the field and physically doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;frameworkmodel-assumptions-and-limitations&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Framework/Model Assumptions and Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model is not perfect. It makes assumptions about a shopper’s ability to walk, locate an item and checkout. These assumptions are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our model assumes the worst possible case for an item’s location — an item is located in the rear corner of the store opposite the shopper’s entrance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shortest possible path to the rear of the store can be traversed via the diagonal; a shopper’s ability to enter the store and walk to the rear via the diagonal (a straight line) represents the optimal path to the rear of the store.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We assume there are minimal impediments to the shoppers ability to walk at the average speed (walking pace of human is assumed).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, we assume a shopper can locate an item that is stocked, pay the cashier, and walk out of the store unencumbered; meaning, at this point we are leveraging this model to gain insight about shop time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite violating the physical properties of a store (i.e., a shopper cannot walk through the aisles of a store via the diagonal), this model provides an insight into reasonable Shop Time expectations for a shopper who is fulfilling a single-item order. For all larger orders, we expect larger Shop Times (Axiom 3); thus, Shop Times recorded below the threshold for all order sizes will be marked as potential outliers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;closing-thoughts-and-reflections&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Closing Thoughts and Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When attempting to model a complex world, sometimes it makes sense to keep your thinking simple. Here we developed a simple model to approximate the time to shop a single-item order. We are now able to use the equation and flag all orders for removal with shop times before the computed threshold for our training set. Let’s end with an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical small-size format &lt;a href=&#34;https://corporate.target.com/article/2018/07/small-format-stores#:~:text=Just%20how%20small%20do%20our,size%20130%2C000%20square%2Dfoot%20store.&#34;&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; is about 40,000 square feet (full-size &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\approx\)&lt;/span&gt; 130,000 sq. ft.). That means we should expect the minimum Shop Time at a small-format Target to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
  \substack{\text{Target (small-size format)} \\ \text{Minimum Shop Time}} \approx \frac{\sqrt{\mbox{80,000}}}{136.4 \frac{feet}{minute}} \approx \mbox{2 (or 2.09) minutes}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
or
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[
  \substack{\text{Target (full-size format)} \\ \text{Minimum Shop Time}} \approx \frac{\sqrt{\mbox{260,000}}}{136.4 \frac{feet}{minute}} \approx \mbox{4 (or 3.78) minutes}
\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now remove all data below these computed thresholds. Amazing how a simple model can have profound impact on one’s thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never say you’ll be back in a minute!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to leave a comment below. 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-V&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on RStudio::Conf 2019 &amp; 2020</title>
      <link>https://davencheicodes.com/post/2020-06-08-rstudio2020-thoughts-and-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davencheicodes.com/post/2020-06-08-rstudio2020-thoughts-and-reflections/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;about-my-first-conference-experience&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About My First Conference Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year ago, My &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shipt.com&#34;&gt;Shiptmate&lt;/a&gt;, Nathan and I went to our first Data Science conference, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/resources/rstudioconf-2019/&#34;&gt;RStudio::Conf 2019&lt;/a&gt; in Austin,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:welcome&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images_2019/welcome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RStudio::Conf 2019 Welcome Presentation&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: RStudio::Conf 2019 Welcome Presentation
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was there that I realized the existence of a large and welcoming community of lovers of not only R, RStudio, et al but also of people. For the first two days of the conference I attended the Deep Learning workshop and Nathan the Tidyverse workshop. I was exposed to deep learning models such as Neural Networks, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-bloggers.com/time-series-deep-learning-forecasting-sunspots-with-keras-stateful-lstm-in-r/&#34;&gt;Long Short Term Memory (LSTM)&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2019/aclu_full_join.jpg&#34; width=&#34;45%&#34; style=&#34;float:right; padding:10px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also stayed to attend the conference. It was there that I was exposed to passionate R developers, talks, and seminars. I heard David Robinson give a presentation called &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/resources/rstudioconf-2019/the-unreasonable-effectiveness-of-public-work/&#34;&gt;The unreasonable effectiveness of public work&lt;/a&gt;. I also heard a really cool presentation on computer science education called &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/resources/rstudioconf-2019/explicit-direct-instruction-in-programming-education/&#34;&gt;Explicit Direct Instruction in Programming Education&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During one of the sessions, I attended Brooke Watson’s presentation for the ACLU titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/resources/rstudioconf-2019/r-at-the-aclu-joining-tables-to-to-reunite-families/&#34;&gt;R at the ACLU: Joining tables to to reunite families&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat feature of a conference is the entertainment. The entertainment at RStudio::Conf 2019 was Willie Nelson’s son, Luke Nelson. He along with a few other bands gave performances at the famous Austin City Limits. Here’s a clip from his performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;video controls&gt;
&lt;source src=&#34;./images_2019/luke_nelson.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures that I took during the conference; among others these include, the gghighlight digital poster, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/resources/rstudioconf-2019/melt-the-clock-tidy-time-series-analysis/&#34;&gt;Earo Wang’s&lt;/a&gt; presentation on TSibble and Tidy Time Series Analysis (all part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tidyverts.org/&#34;&gt;Tidy Verts&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2019/gghighlight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;GGHighlight E-Poster&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
GGHighlight E-Poster
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2019/earo_wang.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Earo Wang Presentation&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Earo Wang Presentation
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2019/funny_comment.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Boston Accent: Git Outta Here 😂&#34; width=&#34;76%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Boston Accent: Git Outta Here 😂
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2019/you.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hadley: YOU, you get a car! 🤣...&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Hadley: YOU, you get a car! 🤣…
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brought us to the end of our visit to Austin, Texas and the conclusion of the 2019 RStudio::Conf with the announcement of the 2020 RStudio::Conf in San Francisco, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2019/2020_conf.jpg&#34; width=&#34;45%&#34; style=&#34;float:right; padding:10px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest takeaway from this conference for me may have been David Robinson’s presentation on public works and sharing your findings for community and personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That talk inspired me to create this site and hopefully (🤞) inspire minorities to journey into the field of Data Science. I was definitely pumped to learn more about machine learning and to attend the 2020 conference is San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;about-my-second-conference-experience&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About My Second Conference Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the month of June 2019, I relocated to my current company’s west coast office in San Francisco, CA. This gave me the chance to attend the 2020 RStudio::Conf without the cost of housing for the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you attend a conference you get some solid swag. Here are a few pics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/shirt_front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Front of tshirt&#34; width=&#34;57%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Front of tshirt
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/shirt_rear.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rear of tshirt&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Rear of tshirt
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/name.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Should have wrote @davencheicodes... 2021!?&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Should have wrote &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;@davencheicodes&lt;/span&gt;… 2021!?
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/cheat_sheet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cheat Sheet&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Cheat Sheet
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/reticulate.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reticulate Cheatsheet&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Reticulate Cheatsheet
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/forecasting.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wish I had a clone...&#34; width=&#34;57%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Wish I had a clone…
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I attended the Applied Machine Learning workshop taught by Max Kuhn. His workshop was fairly intense. It focused on topics including Regression, Decision Trees, and Clustering methods, all in two days. We implemented those methods using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidymodels.org/&#34;&gt;tidymodels&lt;/a&gt; framework. I loved it and would highly recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On day two, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hadleywickham&#34;&gt;Hadley Wickham&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/topepos/&#34;&gt;Max Kuhn&lt;/a&gt; signed their books &lt;a href=&#34;https://adv-r.hadley.nz/&#34;&gt;Advanced R&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feat.engineering/&#34;&gt;Feature Engineering and Selection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/hadley_sig.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Got my personal copy signed!&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Got my personal copy signed!
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/max_sig.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thanks Max!&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Thanks Max!
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final two days are the conference. Here are some pics of the keynote and presentations that I saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/countdown_2002.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Countdown to the 2020 RStudio::Conf!...&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Countdown to the 2020 RStudio::Conf!…
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/keynote1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A keynote video&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
A keynote video
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/keynote2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Y\&#39;all we made it!&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Y&#39;all we made it!
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/keynote3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Value&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Value
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/hadley.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hadley WickhamPpresentation&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Hadley Wickham Presentation
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/hexagon_wall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hexagon Wall&#34; width=&#34;57%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Hexagon Wall
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/hexagon1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Up Close&#34; width=&#34;56%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Up Close
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/excel_joke.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Excel Joke&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Excel Joke
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/pythonandr.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Use R in Production!&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Use R in Production!
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/business_joke.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Preach Brotha. Come on Stakeholders, ask better questions!&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Preach Brotha. Come on Stakeholders. Ask better questions.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/lesson_learned.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lessons!&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Lessons!
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/hyndman.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rob Hyndman #TimeSeries&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Rob Hyndman #TimeSeries 🐐
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/nssd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Not So Standard Deviations Ep. 100&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Not So Standard Deviations Ep. 100
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-6&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/hillary_roger.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hilary Parker and Roger Peng&#34; width=&#34;69%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Hilary Parker and Roger Peng
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:2021conf&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/2021conf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RStudio::Conf 2021 is in Orlando, FL!&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;70%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: RStudio::Conf 2021 is in Orlando, FL!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;closing-thoughts-and-remarks&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Closing Thoughts and Remarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images_2020/rstudio_friends.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;45%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34; style=&#34;float:right; padding:10px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, my biggest takeaways include not only the lessons learned during the workshop but also the cool friendships built with others across the United States. I currently use the Tidy Models framework that Max Kuhn taught us. Moreover, I now understand MARS models. A model type that is used by my current employer - I’ll touch more on this in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the workshop, I sat beside Maliha and later in the conference I met her boss lady, Kelly. Moreover, I made some great connections with other Data Scientist; some at Blue Cross Blue Shield, others at FAANG (Facebook, Amazon, Apple, Netflix, Google). I was also able to ask Yihui Xie a RMarkdown question!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been really great to take the lessons learned at this conference and leverage them in my everyday work. I would say that conference has a high return on time and money spent; RStudio::Conf is one such conference. I would highly recommend attending at least one. I personally believe in my favorite economists &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rajchetty.com/&#34;&gt;Raj Chetty&lt;/a&gt; his work at &lt;a href=&#34;https://opportunityinsights.org/&#34;&gt;Opportunity Insights&lt;/a&gt;, specifically insights and thoughts around &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.equality-of-opportunity.org/assets/documents/inventors_summary.pdf&#34;&gt;Lost Einstiens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for checking out my first post. Stream of consciousness: I’m hoping to write at least once a month. I have completed the framework for my next two posts (one about developing this site, hosting, and the markdown image struggle 😭) and another about data analytics for a company machine learning project; however, current employer has dibs first for their &lt;a href=&#34;https://shipt.tech/&#34;&gt;Medium Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to sharing more as journey into the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See ya in Orlando in 2021 and ROLL TIDE! 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-V&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
